The marketing analytics that we do and report on,
我们对于市场的分析和汇报
provides direction for the entire company.
为公司业务提供了方向
So you'll want to be confident when it comes time to put this into practice.
所以 当你开始真正的市场分析时 你会希望自己对自己有信心
Now, confidence is going to come from experience and practice,
自信心源于经验和练习
but also in knowing that you're approaching things the right way.
同样也来源你认可自己做的市场分析
So let's talk about ways that marketing analytics projects come about,
我们来讲讲市场分析项目的产生背景
how you'll likely get involved early on in your career or with a new business,
你新入职场或者新入某个行业时 你会承担怎样的市场分析工作
and how we can approach it.
以及该怎么做
Because when you step into a role in marketing,
一旦你加入了市场部门
you'll be putting your analytic skills into practice immediately.
你几乎马上就会用到你的分析技能
So the first thing that we can do if you're new to a team,
如果新加入一个市场团队 你需要做的第一件事情
is ask lots of questions.
就是问问题
Questions don't have to come across as you being unskilled or under experienced,
问问题不代表你经验不足或者能力不够
but instead they actually demonstrate confidence.
相反 问问题代表了你的自信
You're making sure that you're approaching things properly and gaining clarity,
通过问问题 你确保了你工作的方向是正确的、清晰的
and you'll gain a lot of respect for doing so.
这是让人值得尊敬的
When you jump into a team or a new project,
刚加入一个团队或者开始一个项目的时候
don't assume the vision is clear,
永远不要预设目标是清晰的
don't assume the data is accurate,
也不要预设数据是准确的
and don't assume that you have the full picture.
也不要假设自己知道所有的信息
When you're new to something,
如果你是新人
that is your opportunity to gain clarity,
这个时候就是你搞清楚事情的时候了
and you'll do that by asking questions.
方法就是问问题
Now, you're slowly becoming more and more armed with taking on
随着你自己承担越来越多的分析项目
individual analytics projects and honing
你会越来越知道该如何做研究
your skills on research and how to use that data.
和利用数据
But there are a few points here to help you be more successful at that.
这里有一些技巧 可以帮助你更好地实现菜鸟的飞跃
For starters, you need to recognize your bias.
作为初学者 你要承认自己的预设偏见
When we work on something,
我们做数据分析的时候
we often want a particular outcome.
通常会希望看到某种预期的结果
We've worked really hard and we've invested a lot of our time,
因为我们做了很多工作 特别不容易
and so it's very easy to have a bias and start to twist
所以很自然地到了最后 就会希望看到预期的结果
the data to tell a version of the story or events that we want.
也会有扭曲数据来讲述一个跟我们预期相符的故事的倾向
You got to stop. It's really important to tell the real story.
你不可以这么做！数据真实性很重要！
Again, big decisions are going to be made on
公司可能会基于这些数据 做出某些重大决定
this data and it'll fall apart if the data is inaccurate.
如果数据不准确 就糟糕了
Another piece as you're starting out is to not be surprised by metrics.
另一点是 做好准备
If you act surprised that you're expected to pull a report or run an analysis,
如果你发现自己需要准备报告或者做分析 就觉得很惊讶
you'll look out of place.
那你就会显得格格不入
Think ahead and begin to be prepared for
要有准备 你肯定会被要去
the fact that you will be asked to participate in an analytics project.
参与到分析项目里
Again, you can always ask for clarity.
当然 如果你不懂 可以问问题
Now another really great thing to do when you're new to a team or
对于一个新人 还有一个很好的建议是
a project is to practice socializing your findings.
练习你的沟通技巧
As you're looking at data and gaining deeper insights about what's going on,
假设你在看数据 然后发现了什么
start talking to other people on your team about it.
你就可以开始跟团队的其他人一起讨论
You'll find that they'll add in additional insights that help you build
你会发现你的同事可以给到你一些很好的帮助 比如告诉你一些历史背景
that layer of history that you need to be better at connecting those dots.
你就可以更好地理解为什么数据是这样子的
Now, you'll find that projects and analytics range from small to large.
项目有大有小
So you'll want to get in the habit of having
你应该勤加练习
good practices so that you're more efficient as they come about.
这样大项目来的时候 你就更有准备了
Let's switch gears, I want to talk about how this starts to show up in your day-to-day.
好了 换一个话题 我来讲讲日常工作部分
For starters, analytics is not an extracurricular activity.
如果你刚入行 数据分析不应该是你工作中不同寻常的部分
It shouldn't be something you do when you have time.
不应该是你有时间的时候才去做的事情
It needs to be baked into your routine.
它应该是你的日常工作
As you start your day,
每天工作伊始
you're going to want to be looking at your most important metrics.
你都应该先去关注你的重要指标
You're going to be expected to know these.
你应该随时知道这些指标的表现
When I'm working with my marketing team,
我自己带一个市场团队的时候
I often ask them randomly how their campaign is performing,
就经常随机地问他们某个营销活动的表现怎样
how sales are doing,
销量怎样
how a particular email did,
某个邮件的效果怎样
and they're expected to know that answer.
他们应该要知道答案
You don't want to be caught off guard.
你不会希望自己被抓到不懂的时候
It's really easy to get locked in the idea that you're going to be
你可能会认为
reporting on these findings in a formal manner,
你只需要把数据放入正式汇报里
at a particular meeting,
或者某个会议上
or maybe after a campaign ends.
或者等到整个营销活动结束
But really, you need to be in that data often
但实际上 你应该随时都知道营销情况
as informal conversations come up all the time.
同事间谈话肯定会不断涉及到
Now later, I'll guide you through what data that you'll want to be tracking at a minimum,
后续我会讲有哪些指标你是一定要追踪的
but for now focus on owning that data.
但目前我们先来讲 你对你的数据应该要有责任感
If there's a problem collecting the data,
如果你收集数据遇到了问题
make it known that you've lost visibility.
要让相关人员知道
Take time to go into deeper insights or delegate them.
然后花时间去解决这个问题
You don't want to wait to let problems creep in,
不要拖到出现问题
and that's why we set a cadence for review.
这也是为什么我们会设置定期回顾
Think about those daily metrics and then what metrics you might need to be
想一想你每天都需要关注的指标 以及
looking at on a weekly, bi-weekly, monthly basis.
你每个星期、每两个星期、每个月需要看的指标
It's also important that you're anticipating the questions
提前准备可能会被问到的问题也很重要
that might be asked and starting to prepare those reports early.
以及尽早准备汇报
You can even build out templates so that you're dropping in the data as you have it.
你甚至可以先建立一个模板 然后再往里面填充数据
Now, how you're involved in analytics is going to vary from job to job.
你的具体分析内容 将因工作而异
You will be involved,
但是肯定的是 你会需要做市场分析
so start planning ahead.
所以尽早准备吧！